Okay, boys and girls.
好啦 小朋友们
Guess what kind of animal Wacky Benny's making now?
猜猜笨蛋本尼现在在做什么动物吧?
Give you a big hint.
给你们个大大的提示哟
Is it a dead animal?
你做的是死动物吗?
I say we put him out of his misery and bring out Emma's cake.
咱们还是赶紧让这孩子歇口气 把Emma的蛋糕端出来吧
He's so new to this. How's he gonna learn if we stop his act?
他是个新手 如果我们不让他做了 他怎么学习进步呢?
You're a sucky clown.
你这个小丑糟透了
And you're a super-duper audience.
你这个观众棒极了
Hey, that is not okay. Hey, keep your hands off my son.
- 嘿 这可不成 - 别动我儿子!
Tell him to keep his hand off me.
叫你儿子先别动我
I can't move my arm or leg.
我的手脚都不能动了
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生 第八季第6集
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生 第八季第6集
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 时间轴：荒川小白脸
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：FFLonestar 墨墨塔 校对：酒囊饭袋 时间轴：荒川小白脸
So how does a completely healthy teenager have a mini-stroke?
为什么一个完全健康的青少年 会忽然发生小型中风呢?
Head CT and cerebral angiogram are normal.
头部CT和脑血管造影都正常
Clotting parameters are normal.
凝血指数也都正常
You're forgetting the wrinkly clump in the middle of his shirt.
你们忘记他衬衣中间那皱巴巴的一块了
Thought we'd diagnose the middle-aged clown first.
我觉得咱还是先诊断这个中年小丑吧
It's probably from my seat belt. Wrinkle pattern's too varied.
- 安全带弄的 - 皱褶不够整齐
It looks like someone shoved you or grabbed you. Probably from the diaper bag.
- 看起来好像谁推了你一把 或者揪你衣服了 - 可能是那尿布袋的缘故
If the patient's using drugs, cocaine could have caused an arterial spasm in his brain.
如果病人在吸毒 可卡因可能造成脑部动脉痉挛
The tox screen was clean.
毒素化验呈阴性
I'm gonna say it was the ex-girlfriend you cheated on,
我说吧 应该是你背着她乱搞的前女友
not the ex-wife you cheated with. If the latter was prone to violence,
而不是和你乱搞的前妻 因为如果后者如此暴力的话
you'd have been scattered in various dumpsters years ago.
你早就变成碎尸被扔进各处的垃圾箱了
Seriously?
你们不是吧?
No one else wants to talk about the patient?
就没人想来讨论下病人?
New office furniture. Meaty topic.
谈谈办公室的新家具吧 多好的话题
What's the action on the ex-wife?
押前妻 最低多少?
It was Rachel's boyfriend Phil.
是Rachel的男朋友Phil
His company's moving him back to Portland.
他的公司要把他召回波特兰
He wants me to change my visitation order
他要我修改我的探视令
so he can ask Rachel and my daughter to move out west with him.
好让他和Rachel带着我女儿搬到西边去
Things got a little heated.
然后大家都有点激动了
The patient was punched in the groin.
病人的裆部被打了一拳
Could have triggered a massive sympathetic discharge.
可能触发了全身性的同体反应
Carotid duplex is normal. Who's better qualified to be the daddy?
颈动脉丛正常 你觉得谁比较有资格当爸爸啊
The guy who spilled a little DNA in her gene pool
那个捐献DNA的家伙呢
or the guy who's gonna be there day and night to pass on important values
还是那个会日夜陪在她身边 教育她
like not shtupping mommy after the divorce?
譬如离婚后就别再来搞我 这种生活美德的那个人呢?
I am her daddy. She's staying here. House has a point.
- 我是她爸爸 她必须得在我身边 - 可House说的没错呀
A couple nights a week with each kid may make you feel better.
和每个小孩呆那么几个晚上可能会让你心里好受些
Doesn't replace two 'round-the-clock parents.
但是不能取代两个全天候家长的责任呀
'Round-the-clock or not, parenting's an impossible job.
不管是不是全天候 做家长本来就是不可能完成的任务
No way not to mess it up. Why shouldn't Taub be the one to do it?
反正总会搞糟的 干嘛不由Taub来执行呢?
- Thank you. - Makes sense.
- 谢谢? - 说得通
Park's tiger mom and dad were so insufferable,
Park的虎妈虎爹是如此地令人发指
she has to measure their affection in hours.
以至于她得用小时衡量他们的关心
Chase's careerist dad and alcoholic mom
Chase的工作狂爹和酒鬼妈是如此冷漠无情
were so indifferent, he has to believe it's a wash.
以至于他不得不相信这就是残酷的现实
Your turn.
该你了
What did your screwed-up parents do to screw up your view of parenting?
你爹娘是怎么毁灭你的家长观的?
They were good parents. That's an oxymoron.
- 他们是很好的家长 - 这根本是自相矛盾
Chase is right. All parents screw up all children.
Chase说得对 所有家长都毁了自己的孩子 而且他现在在做白日梦
but it makes some huge difference if I keep my daughter here or let her move?
但是我让不让我女儿搬走 却能在她的人生中产生重大影响?
Endocarditis.
感染性心内膜炎
Flipd a piece of vegetation into his brain, which could have broken up before the angiogram.
把一块小小的增生组织送入了他的大脑 而有可能在血管造影之前又消解了
Transesophageal echo to confirm.
食道回声测试以确认
Screwed up is your best case.
毁了对你来说都是最好的情况了
Bouncing between a philandering workaholic dad
在一个风流成性的工作狂爹
and an embittered, sexually betrayed mom,
和一个被老公背叛的怨妇妈之间打转
it's gonna lead to screwed-up squared.
你家姑娘这一辈子算是惨定了
Is endocarditis treatable?
感染性心内膜炎能治吗?
Very. The echo will show us any growths on his heart valve.
非常易于治疗 回声测试会显示他心脏中的异常增生
Most likely meds will be enough. He won't even need surgery.
很可能只用药就可以了 连手术都不用做
He's just taken up performing and it's very stressful for him.
他刚刚开始表演 压力挺大的
Could that have caused this? It's not stressful. I have fun.
- 这是不是病因啊? - 我没压力大啊 我挺享受的
Stress wouldn't be relevant, but anything that increases his adrenalin
压力可能不是相关因素 但任何能让他肾上腺素升高的诱因
could have made it worse.
都有可能使病情加重
Maybe we find you a new hobby, one you're a little better at.
也许你应该找一个新的爱好 一个你可能更擅长一点的
I'm gonna get better at it, and it's not a hobby.
我终究会擅长的 而且这也不是爱好
I- I think I want to get a job working as a circus clown,
我想要成为全职的马戏团小丑
making people laugh.
给人们带去欢笑
Ben, I-I don't think that's a good idea. It was good enough for my dad.
- Ben 我不认为这是个好主意 - 可是爸爸会觉得是啊
You're a, uh... no, his biological father.
- 您是...? - 不 他说的是他亲生父亲
Could his dad's melanoma be a factor here?
他父亲的黑色素瘤可不可能会有关系呢?
That wouldn't be related. Ben, you barely knew him.
- 不可能的 - Ben 你都不怎么记得他了
You're such a smart kid.
你这么聪明
You could aim a lot higher than face paint and seltzer bottles.
你能做的事情可比往脸上涂颜料 和扔瓶子要高级多了
I need treatment for my type 2 diabetes.
我需要治疗II型糖尿病
There is absolutely no part of that sentence that is true.
你这话就没有一个字是对的
I've been experiencing weight gain, fatigue, and sluggishness.
我最近体重上升 疲乏而且浑身无力
Weight loss is a symptom of diabetes.
糖尿病的症状是体重下降
Fatigue is a symptom of thinking you have disease you don't actually have,
而疲乏是因为操心你没得的病引起的
and sluggishness is a synonym of fatigue.
而且浑身无力和疲乏是同义词好么
I need Insulin. I know it.
我需要胰岛素 我就知道
Much as I'd like to kill you by dangerously lowering your blood sugar,
虽然我很想通过把你的血糖 降低到危险的程度来干掉你
murder violates my parole.
但是杀人是违反我假释规定的
That bloodwork is week's old. Test me again.
血检都是几周前做的了 再做一次
I am the test. The test is negative.
我比血检还准 明白告诉你啥也没有
The test also thinks you're a giant pain in the ass.
而且你还是个讨厌的刺儿头
That last insult was your cue to leave.
这最后一句骂你的话是让你赶紧走人来着
Test me.
给我做测试
Fine. Wait right here.
好吧 在这等着
Thank you.
谢谢您了
Sleep study.
睡眠测试
Please make sure he's not disturbed for the next eight hours.
请保证接下来的八个小时里没人打扰他
We need to talk about Saturday night.
咱们得说说周六晚上的事儿
No, no, no, no, no.
别别别
Historians will talk of Saturday night, not us.
该谈论周六晚上的是历史学家 可不是咱们
The legendary night on which we watch Santos shatter Rubio's jaw
在那个传奇的晚上 我们将亲眼见证Santos打碎Rubio的下巴
and you epically pay me $50. I have a chance to really watch it.
- 而你乖乖给老子五十大洋 - 我还真有机会亲眼见证
A patient of mine has a pair of tickets he can't use,
我一个病人有两张票 他去不了
and obviously you're under hoe and office arrest.
而你呢 因为要在办公室和家里禁足显然也去不了
I just wanted to make sure you were cool
我只是想确定一下
if I go to without you. Uh, no, thanks.
- 你对我不带你去没有意见 - 不了 谢谢
I'm afraid I'm gonna have to decline your invitation
抱歉我得拒绝你
to not spend Saturday night with you.
星期六晚上不带我玩的邀请
These are ringside seats.
可这是场边的座位!
Cameras are ringside too.
摄像机不也在场边上嘛
If you want, I could sweat and spit and bleed on you from time to time.
如果你想要 我可以不时地 在你身上抹抹汗啊 吐吐痰啊 擦擦血啊什么的
I'd take you if I could. Well, I'd take me if either of us could.
- 如果我可以我肯定就带你去了啊! - 如果我们俩有一个人可以 我就带我去了
See what a tough spot I'm in? I'm going to that fight.
- 看到我多贴心了没? - 这拳赛我是非去不可
All right, I'll take the other ticket.
好啊 那另一张票就归我咯
Let me worry about logistics.
比赛之外的杂事就交给我操心吧
Patient's heart valves are normal. It's not endocarditis.
病人的心脏瓣膜没事 不是感染性心内膜炎
But he has a thickened pericardium, which makes no sense.
但是他的心包有增厚的现象 实在有违常理
He has a heart problem but not one that could have caused his T.I.A.
他的心脏是有问题 但解释不了短暂性脑缺血
Syphilitic vasculitis would explain the T.I.A. And the pericardial inflammation.
梅毒性血管炎可以解释短暂性脑缺血以及心周感染
Syph test was negative.
梅毒测试呈阴性
Plus, the kid's never been sexually active.
另外 这孩子从未有过性行为
Yeah, I got that from the line in his chart that says "birthday clown."
我看到他病历上的"生日小丑"就想到这点了
His late father was a circus clown. Histoplasmosis?
- 他死去的爸爸曾经是马戏团小丑 - 组织胞浆菌病?
He's not immuno-compromised. And I assume you added that irrelevant tidbit
他的免疫系统并未受到抑制 而且我想你毫无必要的来这么一句
because you're moved by the son's idiotic tribute
是因为你被这儿子愚蠢的致敬感动了
and think it justifies keeping your daughter in New Jersey.
并且觉得这可以成为 你把你女儿留在新泽西的又一理由?
What if he has a heightened immune system? I mentioned it because...
- 如果他的免疫系统其实是被增强了呢? - 我提到这个是因为...
Take your time. We'll continue with the medicine.
您慢慢想 我们继续治病救人了
Sjogren's could have given him chronic pericarditis and cerebral arteritis.
Sjogren氏症可能会引起 慢性心包炎以及脑动脉炎
Sjogren's it is. IV immunosuppressant to treat.
就是Sjogren氏症了 静脉注射免疫抑制药物以治疗
Anything?
想出来啥没有?
This will calm your immune system.
这会让你的免疫系统平静下来
Should be out of here within the week.
你可能一周之内就能出院
My mom will be happy to hear that.
我妈听到这个会很高兴的
I've got an internship that starts in three weeks.
我有个实习三周之后就要开始了
I take it it's not at a place with a big top.
我觉得应该不是在马戏团吧?
It's at my stepdad's law office.
是我继父的律师事务所
I know I'm not any good at being a clown yet,
我知道我虽然现在还是个差劲的小丑
but when I do get a laugh
但是如果我表演的时候真有人笑了
and see those kids' eyes light up,
或者看到那些孩子的眼睛亮起来
that's how my dad made me feel when I was a kid.
我就想起我还是个小孩的时候 我爸给我的感觉就是那样的
You need to hang on to that.
你一定要抓住这个
My mom says he was a loving father
我妈妈说他是个慈爱的父亲
but always broke and always on the road.
可就是永远身无分文 四处漂泊
It's just a stupid way to make a living.
这可不是什么正经事业
You're 16. Plenty of time to make money.
你才16岁 挣钱的时间多了去了
Wanting to build a connection with your dad
但是想与你的父亲建立情感上的联系
and pass on some of the joy that he gave you,
并且把他曾给你的快乐传递下去
that's not stupid at all.
是很正经的事
Ooh. I got it.
我来吧
Is, uh, is this because of the medication?
这是药物引起的吗?
Is it normal?
这正常吗?
It's not normal, and it's not Sjogren's.
不正常 而且也不是Sjogren氏症
T.I.A., thickened pericardium,
短暂性脑缺血 心包增厚
and now he's bleeding from his nose and mouth.
而现在鼻腔和口腔出血
What are you doing with her?
你抱她干什么?
"Her"?
"她"?
Surely this bundle of fun has an actual name.
这个小宝贝疙瘩总有名字的吧
It's Sophie.
她叫Sophie
Both your kids are named... She's Sophie. The other one's Sophia.
- 你的两个娃子都叫... - 这个是Sophie 还有一个是Sofia
It different enough. they actually have
- 够不同了吧 - 这俩名字
two completely different derivations.
其实词源不一样的哟
No, they don't.
好吧我乱说的
I wasn't in a strong negotiating position.
我本来也说不上话
Why is she here? Ruby dropped her off.
- 她怎么在这儿? - Ruby把她放这的
Seemed pretty upset. Apparently someone forgot that it was daddy's night.
她挺不高兴的 因为显然某人忘记了昨晚是爹地之夜
She wasn't even gonna leave her
而且我不说今天早放你走
until I said that I was letting you off early.
她都不肯放手呢
Damn it. I just started back on the team. My schedule's a mess.
该死的 我刚回到小队里 时间表都乱成一团了
If your own kids are a scheduling item, maybe you should let one of them move.
如果你的娃子都变成了时间表上的项目 你是该考虑让其中一个挪挪窝了
Patient has low platelets. Makes me think D.I.C.
病人血小板计数很低 我想可能是全身弥漫性凝血
She doesn't seem to like that idea. You're right.
小家伙可不喜欢这个主意 你说得对
He has no schistocytes in his smear.
血涂片中没有裂细胞
He also has a low red count.
红血球记数也很低
What if it's a retroperitoneal bleed?
如果是腹膜后出血呢?
No Grey-Turner's sign. She wasn't fussing like that when I was holding her.
- 无Grey-Turner征 - 我抱她的时候她可一点没闹
Maybe she likes the sound of my voice,
可能她喜欢我说话的声音
which is weird because I have no genetic connection to her.
这可奇了怪了 我们没有血缘关系哟
Could it be she doesn't know the difference?
会不会她不知道懂得分辨呢?
So many children of your own. No wonder you have such insight into my relationship with my babies.
您自己有一大群孩子 毫无疑问您在我和我孩子的关系方面是专家
Good point.
说得好
How could I comprehend that you're too despised to keep them from having the same name,
我又怎么能理解你微不足道 到让俩小孩叫了一个名字
too overwhelmed to remember your own calendar, and too vain to admit that at this stage,
手忙脚乱到连自己的时间表都盯不住 或者死要面子到现在还不承认
you don't matter to either baby.
你在俩小孩的生活中都是一点地位没有
Low white count suggests infection.
白血球计数低代表是感染
What if you're allright?
如果你们都说对了呢?
Low platelets plus low red count
低血小板和红血球计数
plus low white count equals... Aplastic anemia.
- 加上低白血球计数等于... - 再生障碍性贫血
Kid needs a bone marrow transplant.
病人需要骨髓移植
Everyone except Adams, transfuse his platelets till you find a match.
除了Adams之外的所有人 去给病人灌注血小板并寻找配型
You started college a semester late
你上大学晚了一个学期
because you left high school a semester late
因为你高中毕业晚了一个学期
because you had five incompletes in your junior year.
又因为你高二的时候有五门课未完成
And you're offering one bad semester as proof that my parents screwed me up?
一个糟糕的学期就足以证明我爸妈毁了我?
Did okay before that. Straight as after that.
之前成绩不错 之后分数全A
I went through a rebellious phase. Don't tell me.
- 我那时叛逆期 - 别跟我说啊
Mom and dad were at each other's throats
你爹娘整天吵个不停
and the academic crisis was a cry for help.
学业上的滑坡其实是你的求救信号
Sorry to mess with your world view,
抱歉我混淆您世界观了
but I'm not messed up, so my parents couldn't have messed me up.
但是我就不是一糟糕的人 所以我爸妈也就无从让我糟糕了
Mom's HLA is only a 3/6 match.
妈妈的HLA只有3/6配型吻合
Maternal grandmother's worse than that.
姥姥还不如这
Where did you unload the baby?
你把孩子扔哪去了?
- Maternity ward. - Shut up.
产科 啥也别说了
You realize you're making House's argument for him.
你这简直是在给House找理由说你
The part where he said any parent who uses day care should ship their child across the country?
他难道要说需要托儿所的家长 都该把自家小孩送到美国另一头去?
No, the part where he said that baby doesn't need you.
不 他要说这孩子根本不需要你
You've only got her a couple days a week and most of that's spent with a rotating cast of nurses.
你一周和她在一起本来就几天 大部分时间还都让她和护士们呆在一起
That's how daddy likes to spend his time too. Shut up.
- 爹地也喜欢那样哟 - 快闭嘴
First cousin's also a whiff. So much for genetics mattering.
- 大表哥也完蛋了 - 基因学什么的见鬼去吧
I'll try the marrow registry.
我来试试骨髓数据库
- Dr. - Park is searching the registry.
Park医生正在数据库中寻找配型
Transfusing his platelets will keep him healthy while we wait.
输入血小板可以让他 在我们等待的时候保持健康
Are you sure there's no one on the father's side of the family?
你真的确定他父亲那边没有人了?
If one of them's a match, that'd speed things up a lot.
如果他们之中有人配型符合 那可就省事了
His parents died young. He was an only child.
他的父母早死了 他又是独子
There's no living relatives that I know of. Something will turn up soon.
- 据我所知他没有在生的亲戚了 - 很快会有结果的
How soon is soon? Will he miss a lot of school? I'm actually thinking of just getting my ged.
多快? 他会错过很多课程吗?
How do you expect to get into a good college?
那样你还怎么进好大学啊
I'm gonna take classes on magic and juggling and try to make a go of this.
我想上魔术和杂技课试一试
Ben, you keep your grades up, you can do anything in the world.
Ben 如果你成绩好 走遍天下都不怕
Like what? Work in some boring office?
走什么天下? 就是坐坐办公室?
I mean, do you think my father would have done that for ten minutes?
你觉得我爸会甘心这样吗?
You don't remember your father. You don't know...
你一点都不记得你爸了 你不知道...
I want to build a connection with him,
我想和他建立情感上的联系
pass on some of the... The joy that he gave me.
把他给我的快乐...传递下去
My, uh, my back hurts. Uh...
我的背疼
His BP is dropping.
血压在急剧下降
We think we've dealt wit all the liability issues.
我觉得我们已经处理好了所有的法律问题...
I'm in a meeting. Sorry.
- 开着会呢 - 抱歉哈
Since you paged me, I didn't want to keep you waiting.
您不是呼我了么 我哪敢让您等着
Yeah, I paged you, which means you're next.
是啊 我呼你是把你排在下一个
That's cool. I'll wait.
好的好的 我等就是了
That's a good start. Let's go through it point by point.
开头不错 我们再一条一条地过一遍
First up...
首先...
I'll call you back.
过会儿再打给你们
Just got this.
刚接到这个
The American Associate of Rheumatology
美国风湿病学联合会发来的
wants you to speak, 9:00, Saturday, in Atlantic City.
想请你星期六九点钟在大西洋城演讲
Dr. Neusinger canceled on them at the last minute.
Neusinger医生在最后一刻取消了
Hmm. I hate conferences.
医学大会什么的 最讨厌了
This is a big one, and it's the premium slot.
这可是个重要会议 而且演讲时间显要
I'd like you to do it.
我希望你能去
I'll clear it with your parole officer.
我亲自跟你的假释官说
What do I need to do for you?
你想让我帮你做点啥?
Halve the clinic hours that you recently doubled
把你最近加倍的门诊时间再减回去
and double the hooker budget that you recently halved.
把你最近减掉的小姐基金再加回来
I think you refer to it as petty cash.
就是你叫零用钱的那个
Fine.
好吧
Just one thing.
还有一点
I'm gonna ask them to put you on in the morning.
我会让他们把你挪到早上
We're doing them a favor. Why should you have to spend the night?
是我们帮他们的忙 凭什么要求你耽误一晚上呢?
You said that 9:00 was the premium slot.
你不是说九点时间显要嘛
I mean, I want to feel like I've earned my hookers.
我是说 我得觉得我堂堂正正地挣来了小姐钱呀
The place'll be a madhouse, especially since it's two miles from the Rubio fight
那地方肯定到时要炸锅了 因为离Rubio那场比赛也就两英里远
at the exact same time.
而且时间也一样
Nice try. You called up, pretended to be Neusinger,
不错么 你给他们打电话 装成Neusinger
cancelled, and suggested yourself as a replacement.
取消会议安排 然后推荐自己作为候补
You go to that fight, you go to prison.
敢去看比赛 就回监狱去
But that'd be redundant, when I have an angry black guy
那不是多余了么 现在我面前不就有个气鼓鼓的黑佬
waiting for me to drop the soap right here.
正等我弯腰捡肥皂么
Better go do some of those clinic hours I recently doubled.
现在赶紧去做我最近加倍了的门诊吧
Test my urine.
验我的尿
Looks like I was wrong about my diagnosis. Yeah. I have diabetes.
- 看来我的诊断错了嘛 - 我有糖尿病!
No, but you're not a hypochondriac
不 你不是个疑病症患者
or you would have imagined some new disease after I shot down the first one.
要不在我拆穿第一个之后 你就会编一个新的出来了
So whose urine is that? Diabetic girlfriend without health insurance?
这是谁的尿啊? 没有医疗保险的糖尿病女朋友?
It's not a scam. I'm sick.
我没骗人 我真病了
Now I have swollen ankles. The medical term is cankles.
- 现在我脚踝都肿了 - 医学术语那叫肉脚环
Is there some black market in Insulin that I don't know about?
你没搞什么我不知道的黑市胰岛素吧?
It's in my genes. My old man got diabetes at 50.
我有遗传的 我爹50岁的时候得了糖尿病
My older brother got it at 50. I just turned 50.
我哥50也得了 我刚刚50
Well, it's a great argument if diabetes was a gold watch.
如果糖尿病是块金表的话 你这论断就再正确不过了
I got sciatica, like my dad.
我跟我爹一样得了坐骨神经痛
Class-four hemorrhoids, like him. I need to get a jump on this thing.
四类痔疮 像他一样 这次我得提早治疗
We had to stop the transfusion.
我们不得不停止输血
Patient's having an allergic reaction to donor platelets. No one in mom's family's a match,
- 病人对血小板产生了过敏反应 - 母亲的家族里无人匹配
and as far as she knows, dad has no living relatives.
而且就她所知 父亲没有在生亲属
It's been years since he died.
他已经去世多年
If the kid's dad died young of melanoma,
如果这孩子的爸爸因为黑色素瘤早早去世了
how come the overprotective mom never took him to a dermatologist?
那么他大惊小怪的妈 为什么从来没带他去看过皮肤科医生?
Are you gonna test my urine or what?
尿你到底验不验?
Not diabetes.
不是糖尿病
Use cross-matched platelets.
用交叉配型符合的血小板
Try to find the patient some blood that's closer to his own.
去给病人找些和他自身血液相似的血来
And get the real story on clown, senior's death.
并且找出小丑爸爸到底怎么了
Mom's hiding something.
妈妈对我们隐瞒了真相
It's a good bet that it's medically relevant.
很有可能和真正的病因有关
Apple juice.
苹果汁
Easiest way to fake a spike in blood sugar.
装血糖过高这个最好用了
His family history of melanoma
黑色素瘤的家族病史
may have affected his cellular outlook.
可能影响了他的细胞形态
If we had more data on the exact type of melanoma his father had...
如果我们能知道他父亲确切得的是 哪种黑色素瘤的话...
Otherwise, we might not be able to find a marrow match.
否则我们有可能找不到配型合适的骨髓
He never had melanoma. How did he die?
- 他没得黑色素瘤 - 那他怎么死的?
He didn't.
他也没死
He lives in pennsauken under a different name,
他用一个假名住在彭萨根
Mitchell Gordon.
Mitchell Gordon
How could you keep this from me? From Ben?
你怎么能对我隐瞒这个? 还瞒着Ben?
He really needs to know his dad just breezed in and out of his life,
他需要知道他父亲在他的生命中来去匆匆
drunk and incoherent?
酗酒而且神志不清吗?
It's better to think the man's dead but decent.
让他觉得他爸虽然死了但是个好人总要好点吧
You realize I have to invite someone else to the Rubio fight?
你总意识到我得找别人陪我去看Rubio比赛的吧
- Nope. - No realization whatsoever.
没 才没这个意识呢
You have a LoJack on your leg. I was happy watching the fight on pay-per-view.
- 您脚上有个脚环好么 - 我本来看个付费频道也就知足了
You're the one who insisted we go to Atlantic City.
是你非嚷嚷着要咱去大西洋城
Your biological father was a decent, God-fearing minister.
你的生父是个敬拜上帝的正经牧师
The guy who raised you was a cold-hearted jerk.
养你的那家伙是个冷酷无情的混账
I'm trying to figure out why you're so convinced
我就不明白你为啥那么确信
Adams has parentally inflicted damage.
Adams就非得被她爹娘伤害过
You're trying to deflect. Now you are.
- 你这是转移话题 - 转移话题的是你
You have to believe that every parent screws up every child
你要么相信每个父母都毁了自己的孩子
or you were screwed out of a decent childhood.
要么相信你自己有个被毁了的童年
My decent daddy of the cloth
我在教堂做事的正经爹
was also being indecent with my married mom.
可和我结了婚的妈干了不正经的事情哟
He probably would have taken other kids to the playground.
他说不定还带着其他孩子去过游乐场呢
It's not my fault. Bad parenting.
不是我的错哟 家教不好
Mitchell Gordon? I've already got a religion. Go away.
- Mitchell Gordon? - 我已经有宗教信仰了 滚
We're doctors.
我们是医生
Your son Ben is in the hospital, at Princeton-Plainsboro.
你的儿子Ben正在PPTH 他病得很重
Yeah, well, I don't have a son. Not anymore.
我没有儿子 现在没有了
We know there are some issues there, but your bone marrow could cure him.
我知道你们有矛盾 但你的骨髓说不定能救他的命
There's a hospital two miles from here. It's a simple test.
医院离这里只有两英里 测试也很简单
You said he was at Princeton-Plainsboro?
你不是说他在PPTH吗?
His mother feels it's better to do the test at a different hospital.
他妈妈认为还是让你在其他医院接受测试比较好
Well, I guess I don't have a son anymore.
那好吧 我已经没有儿子了
House isn't gonna give up.
House不会就此收手的
Just tell him about your parents or make up a lie.
就跟他说说你父母吧 或者撒谎也行
I don't want to lie.
我不想撒谎
I don't want to validate his ridiculous theory.
也不想证实他荒谬的理论
It's not ridiculous.
一点也不荒谬
En the best-intentioned parents end up damaging their kids.
就算最好的家长也会最终毁了自己的孩子
You're a smart, successful doctor.
你是个聪明成功的医生
How much damage could you have?
你身上能有多少伤口呢?
Know how I got interested in medicine?
知道我是怎么开始对医学感兴趣的吗?
When my mother drank, she couldn't handle me,
我妈喝醉了 管不了我的时候
so she locked me in my father's study.
就把我锁在我爸的书房里
Only so many hours you can cry and bang on the door
哭啊 砸门啊 你也就有劲坚持几个小时
before you give up, find something to read.
而在你无力倒地之前呢 找点东西来读读总是好的
We all have family dysfunction.
我们都有家庭残缺
That's why we're successful. To fill that hole.
这就是我们为何成功 为了填满那个缺口
My parents have a lot of money,
我的父母十分富裕
but they didn't make it legally.
但财富却非合法所得
White-collar crime? It started with card games.
- 白领犯罪? - 是从赌博开始的
High-stakes poker.
大赌注的赌博
Then my dad got into narcotics,
然后我爸开始沾染毒品
at first just selling but then using too,
首先是贩毒 之后是吸毒
or he never would have gotten into the slave trade.
否则他也就不会踏入奴隶贸易这行当
Children mostly. Easier to pack in small crates.
贩运的都是孩子 因为容易塞到箱子里去
Plus the shipping's a lot cheaper.
而且运输费用也低
Won't even trust a co-worker.
连同事都不相信
What did your parents do to you?
你爹娘到底把你怎么了?
You have to go see him yourself.
你得自己去找他了
He wouldn't even ce to the door a second time.
他第二次连门都不肯开
Okay. I'll drive over there.
好吧 我开车去
It's a pleural effusion. He had a bleeding problem earlier.
- 是胸腔积液 - 前一阵子的出血问题
Must be bleeding into his lungs.
可能影响到他的肺了
Except there's no blood. What does it mean?
- 但是没有血啊 - 这到底是怎么回事啊?
It means you don't have to make that drive. The problem isn't his marrow.
你不用去找他爸了 问题不在骨髓
It's his liver.
是他的肝脏
- Liver failure. - Explains everything.
肝脏衰竭 一切都能解释了
The question is, what explains the liver failure? It's not an infection.
- 问题是 什么又能解释肝脏衰竭呢 - 不是感染
We tried antibiotics, but he's not responding. More curiously, what explains the mom
- 我们试过抗生素了 没有反应 - 更让我好奇的是 妈妈撒谎说爸爸已经死了
lying about dad pushing up squirting daisies?
又要怎么解释呢?
This is how you plan to get to the boxing game?
你就打算这样去看拳击表演吗?
Why are you looking at her?
你看她干嘛?
'Cause I'm stunned, and I have to look at something.
因为当时我就震惊了啊 总得看点啥吧
Match, bout, fight, contest, day, Helena.
比赛 碰撞 大战 竞赛 那一日 海伦娜
Almost anything works after "boxing," except the word "game."
说拳击赛用啥词都行 就是不能用"表演"
Your bigger problem is, the people who design those things aren't idiots.
你面对的更大问题是 设计那玩意的人可不是傻逼
Can you believe she used to work in the can?
你相信她曾经在监狱里打工么?
Nothing is tamper-proof. It's a synthetic problem.
- 没什么东西是动不了的 - 可能是综合性的问题
His liver's not synthesizing proteins, so fluid is leaking out of his blood vessels.
他的肝脏没有在正常地合成蛋白 所以他的血管发生了液体渗漏
And mom's a selfish jerk. She traded up, married a lawyer,
而且他妈是个自私的混蛋 蹬了他爹 嫁了个律师
wants to forget the lowly circus clown.
想要把那个卑微的小丑永远忘掉
You're defending the father because you feel like a jerk for baking buns in two different ovens.
你替爸爸说话的原因是你觉得 自己在两个炉子里烤面包也不是什么好东西
You want to believe the mythical biological connection excuses being a man slut.
你想要相信成为荡男有生理上的奇妙借口 哎哟!
I don't know why I'm starting to doubt your expertise.
我不知道我为啥忽然开始怀疑你的专业技术了
You do have a classified ad and a piece of metal. It's temperature that sets it off, not force.
- 你的确登了分类广告 而且手里也有家伙 - 触发它的是温度 不是力量
The rivets go pop, I slide in the heating pad. Easy peasy.
把铆钉掀起来 我把加热垫一放 万事大吉
More likely the patient has a hyperammonemic problem.
很可能病人有高血氨症
His liver's not cleaning out his blood. The buildup of toxins is causing everything.
他的肝脏没有在清洁血液 积累起来的毒素造成了所有问题
I'm defending the dad because he got screwed. After he lost his son, he lost his job.
我替他爹说话是因为他爹被摆了一道 儿子丢了 工作也丢了
Been in and out of rehab, ve up clowning.
在戒毒所几进几出 小丑也不做了
Yes, as a parent, I empathize. I say we tell the kid.
作为一个家长 我感同身受 我说我们跟孩子说实话
He's a minor, the mom's his guardian, and it's not even medically relevant.
他是未成年人 妈妈是他监护人 而且这和病情根本没有关系
She robbed them of 12 years together. Or she ripped off the band-aid too late.
- 她夺去了他们12年在一起的时间 - 或者她撕下创可贴的时间太晚了
That memory that she let son of Bozo establish
她给小丑儿子留下了记忆
is making him chase his father's moronic profession
让他追寻起他爹的抽风职业来了
when he could be living the high life in Portland.
他本可以在波特兰好好生活的
And I mean that metaphorically, of course.
我当然只是打个比方
This is where you dazzle me with your contingency plan.
现在给咱看看你的后备计划吧
I see why employers are reluctant to hire ex-cons.
我明白为什么大家都不爱雇用有前科的罪犯了
Well, what about the patient?
病人的情况如何呢?
Is the problem hyperammonemic or synthetic?
是高氨血症呢还是造血功能障碍呢?
Can't treat for both. One requires hemodialysis, the other a liver transplant,
不可能两者皆有 前者需要透析 后者要肝移植
and we couldn't even get the kid a marrow match.
而我们不能找到和这孩子匹配的骨髓移植
Get the mom's consent to pump him full of protein.
让他妈妈同意抽取他的蛋白质
If it's a synthetic problem, more fluid will leak into h chest and his heart will fail.
可如果是造血功能障碍的话 更多的液体会流入他的胸腔 他的心脏会衰竭的
If it's hyperammonemic, toxins will overwhelm his body and he'll go into a coma.
如果是高氨血症的话 毒素会入侵他全身 他会昏迷过去
Do you only like tests that involve the risk of death?
你就只喜欢可能把别人整死的检查吗?
There are some slower, less conclusive tests, but why take that risk?
是有见效慢 效果又不好的检查 但我们为什么要冒那个险呢?
In here.
就在这
Oh, my God. The water.
哦 天啊 水呀
This is completely my fault.
这都怪我
There are very serious risks, but if we don't figure out what he has,
检查风险很高 但如果我们弄不清楚 他到底患什么病
we can't treat him at all.
我们就无法治疗他
I may be a little out of bounds here, but in case there are complications,
我这么说可能有点冒犯了 但以防万一
it might be a good time to come clean to your son,
可能是时候跟你儿子把事情说清楚了
let his father visit. A little out of bounds?
- 让他父亲来看他 - 这是有点冒犯吗?
I don't know the history, but everyone makes mistakes.
我不知道你们的过去 但是人都会犯错的
Your son worships him. Doctor's right about that.
- 你的儿子崇拜他 - 医生说的对
Oh, yeah? And when did he learn that?
是吗? 他什么时候学会的那些?
When he encouraged Ben to drop out of school?
他劝Ben辍学的时候?
Mitchell is not Ben's father any more than a sperm donor would have been.
Mitchell除了贡献了他的精子 他没担负起任何当Ben父亲的责任
Dr. House?
House医生?
Unless you're a locksmith or an electrician with political contacts, I'm busy.
除非你是有政府合同在身的锁匠或电子技师 否则我忙着呢
My husband saw you in the clinic.
我丈夫在门诊找您看过病
Wants treatment for diabetes. My condolences on your forthcoming divorce.
- 想治糖尿病 - 对你即将到来的离婚 我深表遗憾
He keeps imagining symptoms,
他不停地幻想出各种症状
and now I have to make him these awful anti-diabetic meals.
现在我不得不给他做恶心的抗糖尿病饭菜
Since I have no intention of testing him,
鉴于我没有闲情逸致来检查他
treating him, or cooking for him...
治疗他 或给他做饭...
Could you write me a fake prescription for Insulin?
你能给我开张假的胰岛素处方吗?
The advantage of fake prescriptions is, you don't have to be a real doctor to write one.
假处方的好处就是 不是真的医生也能开
Just tell me what's safe to inject in his thigh.
你只需告诉我给他注射什么安全就行
His symptoms will go away
他的症状就会消除
and then I can show him he was never sick.
然后我就能证明他并没有生病了
Water?
水可以吗?
Imaginary medicine is not my specialty.
想象中的药物并非我擅长的
I do have an imaginary colleague
可我有一个想象中的同事
who's just sent me an imaginary page. Imagine how sorry I am.
刚刚在想象中传呼了我 想象下我是多遗憾吧
Still mad about what happened in the lab?
还为刚才实验室里发生的事情生气呢?
I'm not mad. I'm being professional.
我没生气 我这是职业的表现
You claim you're not screwed up. You may even believe it.
你声称你没被毁掉 你可能还相信这点
But House doesn't and I don't, so you can wait till he camps out on your parents' lawn
但House不信 我也不信 所以你可以等到他去你父母家的草坪上安营扎寨
or you can admit you don't live on some higher plane and thank me later.
或者你可以承认你过得并不是那么乐天无忧 之后好好谢谢我
My, uh, my eye feels weird.
我的眼睛感觉很难受
What's happening to me?
我怎么了?
You look tired. I hate it when people say that.
- 你看上去很累 - 我讨厌别人这么说
I know, I look bad. I thought you were gonna go to bed early last night.
- 我知道 我气色很不好 - 我以为你昨晚很早就睡觉了
Like an idiot, I went out with my girlfriends to pretend I have a life,
我就像个白痴一样 昨晚跟我女朋友出去 假装我有自己的生活
when all I did was flirt with guys who'd have no interest in a mom,
和我调情的男人对妈妈都毫无兴趣
miss the baby I couldn't wait to get rid of, and then get yelled at by my mom for staying out too late.
我还想着这个我无法摆脱掉的孩子 之后又因为太晚回家被我妈妈骂
- You need your own place. - Yes.
- 你需要自己的空间 - 是的
I moved back home because it was too drafty at the four seasons. So go back to work at the hospital.
- 我没钱才搬回家的 - 那就回医院上班啊
Day care costs more than what I earned as a nurse.
日托比我当护士一天挣的还要贵
Have you considered sub-standard day care?
你考虑过一些低标准的日托吗?
Why don't you stay here toght?
你今晚何不留下来呢?
No. I mean, in the guest room.
不 我是说 住在客房
I'll watch the baby again, and you can get a real night's sleep.
我会看着孩子 你可以好好睡一觉
You'd do that?
可以吗?
Win-win.
双赢嘛
Mommy gets a rest, daddy gets more time with his little angel.
妈妈可以歇一歇 爸爸可以有更多的时间 和他的小天使在一起
There's some sweats in the closet in the back.
后面的衣帽间有运动衣
Lucky girl.
幸运的小姑娘
Gets another sleepover with da-da.
又可以和爸爸一起睡啦
It makes a difference.
还是有点不同的
Doesn't it?
不是吗?
Didn't answer your page last night. Sorry. Battery died.
- 你昨晚没回复传呼 - 抱歉 电池没电了
We got the patient's eye back in place with steroid injections,
我们给病人注射类固醇 让他眼睛恢复原状了
but a bulging eyeball means it's not a liver problem.
但眼球肿胀意味着不是肝脏的问题
And mom's determination to keep dad away,
妈妈决意不让爸爸来
even as her kid gets sicker and sicker, means she's got more to hide.
即使她孩子的病越来越严重了 说明她有更多事情要隐瞒
It's not diagnostically relevant. Let's let it drop.
这和诊断无关 我们别多管闲事了
You just lost my vote. You flip-flopped on parental rights.
我刚决定不支持你了 你倒戈支持父母的权利
I've been trying to persuade the mother, but it's her son, so it's her call.
我一直尝试说服母亲 但这是她儿子 她有权决定
Well, that very evolved of you.
啊 你思想进化得可真快啊
Don't usually see Darwinian changes over breakfast.
一顿早餐的功夫 就发生进化可真不常见
You made nice-nice with Phil, you decided that
你和Phil妥协了 你终于决定
he'd make a decent father for thing 2 after all.
让他当你二女儿的体面老爹
I had Sophie again last night and Ruby slept in my guest room,
我昨天又照看了Sophie一晚 Ruby睡在我客房
which has nothing to do with Phil,
这和Phil的事半毛钱关系都没有
who will never be a father to my children.
他绝对不会成为我孩子的父亲
Angioneurotic edema can cause rapid swelling.
昆克氏病会引起急性水肿
Hey, we're having a conversation here. No abdominal pain.
嘿 我们这正说着话呢 但没出现腹部疼痛
So that must have been nice, having Ruby and the baby under one roof.
那感觉一定很好喽 和Ruby和孩子在一间屋里
Yes, it was nice having my daughter in my home.
是的 和我女儿一起在家感觉好极了
That's why I would like her sister to live near my home.
所以我希望她妹妹也住在我家附近
Anasarca? Swelling would have followed gravity.
- 全身性水肿? - 那样的水肿会随重力而变化的
Isn't that getting this whole parenting thing ass backwards?
这不是让整件为人父母的事情 本末倒置了吗?
Aren't you supposed to figure out what you can sacrifice to maximize their niceness?
你不就是想看看为了她们的最优 你能牺牲什么吗?
And do you think I should sacrifice myself from their lives?
那你认为我应该在她们的生活中消失掉?
Just one life,
你只有一个
until the other one's mommy meets someone nicer than you.
直到另外一个妈妈遇到一个比你更好的人
Swelling that fast and localized has to come from the lymph nodes.
局部肿得那么快一定是淋巴结肿胀造成的
Burkitt's lymphoma.
伯基特氏淋巴瘤
Swelling. Cankles.
浮肿 脚腕有赘肉
That's not a symptom of Burkitt's.
这不是伯基特氏淋巴瘤的症状
- Are you saying it's... - It's Burkitt's.
- 你是说这不是... - 就是伯基特氏淋巴瘤
Prep him for chemo.
给他上化疗
I think you should give House permission to go to Atlantic City.
我觉得你应该允许House去亚特兰大
We'll stop by the rheumatology conference.
我们会顺道去风湿病会议
Everyone's covered. No.
- 每个人的需求都照顾到了 - 不行
The guy has earned the right to go to one boxing match.
他干的活应该让他去看场拳击比赛
He's done everything you've asked... Funded and staffed his own department.
你要求的一切他都做到了... 自己找资金 组建他的部门
Hasn't even broken as much as a traffic law.
甚至没怎么有过交通违章
You're right.
你说的对
So you'll let him go? No.
- 所以你同意让他去喽? - 没有
I get why he wants to go to that fight. I'd love to go myself,
我明白他为什么想去看比赛 我自己也想去
which is kind of why I have to stop him. My job is to be the jerk.
这也是我必须阻止他的原因 我的工作就是扮演一个混蛋
House has to believe that I have authority over him.
House必须相信他逃不出我的手掌心
He can't function under someone's thumb.
可让他完全被人掌控 是行不通的
I know, which means you can't go either.
我知道 所以这意味着你也不能去
Your job is to be his friend, to stay here and sit with him
你的工作就是当他的朋友 待在这 陪他
and watch the fight on pay-per-view while bitching about me.
一边看比赛转播 一边咒骂我
If we both do our jobs, we might actually get him through his parole.
如果我们都做好我们的工作 我们可以让他摆脱假释状态
You're right.
你说的对
Sorry to show up like this.
抱歉 我们来得这么突然
I was expecting a battery of lawyers. No lawyers.
- 我原来以为是一大群律师来找我呢 - 没有律师
Phil had something that he would like to say,
Phil想跟你说几句话
so I thought that he should say it in person.
我觉得他亲自跟你说比较好
It was wrong of me to confront you about taking Rachel to Portland.
跟你说我要把Rachel带到波特兰是错的
You don't want to move to Portland?
你不想搬去波特兰了?
Of course I do, but this is about your daughter too
我当然想 但这也关系到你女儿
and I'm not gonna do something like this without your support.
不得到你的支持 我是不会这么做的
So you guys are trying to manipulate me
所以你们是想来操控我
by playing good cop/good cop?
通过俩人都装好人?
Is that how little you think of me?
你以为我这么卑鄙吗?
It's clear you're back working for House.
你又回来给House干活就说明你心灵多黑暗
I will see you this weekend when you pick up Sophie.
你这周末去接Sophie时再见
Sophia. We actually started calling her Sophie.
- 她叫Sophia - 我们开始叫她Sophie了
Yeah.
是的
Great. It's cute.
很好 名字很可爱
Cankles.
脚踝赘肉
Is there some problem with the prescription you gave me?
你给我的处方有问题吗?
I'm faint. I've been gaining more weight.
我头晕 我一直在长肉
I think I need a bigger dose. If you double his placebo, he might drown.
- 我觉得应该加大我的剂量 - 如果你加倍他的安慰剂 他就淹死了
Also, you forgot to mention that your heart rate is slow.
而且 你忘了提你的心率过缓
My... my heart rate is not...
我的心率不...
52. The technical term is slow.
- 52 - 医学用语是过缓
Those awful anti-diabetic meals you eat, do they contain bok choy?
那些你吃的恶心的抗糖尿病食物 里面有白菜吗?
A pound of it. Every day.
有很多 每天都吃
Bok choy has glucosinolates which inhibit thyroid function
白菜里面有芥子油甙 会抑制甲状腺功能
and account for all your symptoms.
引起了你所有的症状
So this isn't diabetes?
所以这不是糖尿病喽?
You have a bad case of irony.
你这个病很讽刺
The food that you're eating to stop making you sick is making you sick.
你吃的为了防止你得病的食物 恰恰是让你生病的
Hey, maybe I don't have my father's crummy genes after all.
嘿 也许我没遗传到我父亲糟糕的基因
On the other hand, maybe you're fat enough to get diabetes even without him.
不过 你这么胖 没遗传基因 也离得糖尿病不远了
I can't believe I have cancer.
我不敢相信我得了癌症
We caught it early. You should be okay.
我们发现得早 你会没事的
I could die. I never went anywhere, did anything.
我会死的 哪都去不了 什么都做不了
If my father had lived,
如果我父亲还活着的活
everything would have been different.
一切都会大不一样
Your mom and stepdad love you.
你的妈妈和继父很爱你
They've given you a great home.
他们给了你一个很好的家
That counts for a lot.
这样已经很不错了
He's crashing. Everything's shutting down.
他不行了 所有的器官都在衰竭
Renal failure, lung failure, heart failure, all before we started chemo.
肾衰竭 肺衰竭 心脏衰竭 一切都发生在我们开始化疗前
Burkitt's lymphoma is fast-moving, but not this fast.
伯基特氏淋巴瘤发病是迅速 但没这么迅速
No rush. ICU stands for take your time in Latin.
别着急 ICU拉丁文的意思就是慢慢来
Multiple aneurysms.
多重动脉瘤
That would mean that every symptom after his T.I.A.
那就说明在他短暂性脑缺血发作后的所有症状
was a coincidence. Cholesterol emboli?
- 都是巧合 - 胆固醇栓塞?
Bingo. Fits perfectly. Check the file.
对喽 太符合了 检查下病历
Confirm that we did major abdominal surgery on him
确认我们给他动过腹部手术
and then completely forgot about it.
然后把这个诊断忘得一干二净吧
House.
House
Hello?
你好?
What the hell are you doing here? I was told that this might be my last chance to see my son.
- 你来这干什么? - 我被告知这可能是我见到儿子的最后机会了
You had no right! This is none of your business!
你没有权利! 这不关你的事!
- I didn't. - I called him.
- 我没有 - 我把他叫来的
This man's Ben's hero.
这个人是Ben心目中的英雄
Let them spend five minutes together.
让他们在一起待五分钟吧
No! Get out of here!
不! 滚出去!
Wait.
等等
You sexually molested your son. Your walk.
你性侵过你的儿子 你走路的样子
Tabes dorsalis.
你得了脊髓痨(一种实质性梅毒)
You have late-stage syphilis,
你梅毒晚期
which you gave to our patient presumably 12 years ago,
你在大概12年前传染给了我们的病人
which also explains why mom is not big on family reunions.
这也解释了为什么妈妈不想让你们父子见面
I shouldn't be here.
我不应该来这
We tested him for syphilis. He was negative.
我们给他检测过梅毒啊 结果是阴性的
After 12 years, the active infection would have died down
事情过了12年 他身体里的活性病毒早就死了
everywhere except the arteries in his brain, where it could hide out from our tests.
除了脑动脉里面的 所以才躲过了我们的检查
But when that six-year-old heckler punched him in his juggling pins,
但当那个六岁的捣蛋鬼打了他下体一拳后
it kicked up the dormant bacteria in his pelvis.
唤醒了他骨盆里面休眠的细菌
The immunosuppressants we gave him sent it into overdrive.
我们给他的免疫抑制剂超过了他的负荷
The antibiotics we gave him actually started destroying the syphilis.
我们给他的抗生素实际上有开始消灭梅毒菌
But like pouring water on a fire,
但就像往火上浇水一样
that led to a trail of toxic smoke and ash
那让毒素冒烟 燃成灰烬
which made his immune system overcompensate.
这引起他的免疫系统过度补偿
Severe Jarisch-Herxheimer reaction.
严重的疗后梅毒增剧反应
Is this true? Yes, Jarisch-herxheimer is real.
- 这是真的吗? - 是的 疗后梅毒增剧反应是真的
It sounds silly, but...
听上去有点二 但是...
Oh, you mean the... the... right.
哦 你是说... 是的
I found stains on his clothes.
我在他衣服上发现了污迹
He didn't understand and he didn't seem traumatized.
他不明白 他看上去像是没受过伤害一样
I kept trying to talk to him, but before long, he'd forgotten,
我一直试着想和他谈谈 但过不了多久 他就忘了
and he seemed...
他看上去...
And he seemed happy and he seemed normal.
他看上去快乐又正常
So you made daddy go away and you made sure junior had no reason to go looking.
所以你让他爸爸离开 又确保孩子不会到处找他
I was just trying to protect him,
我只是想保护他
like I should have done from the start.
就像我开始应该做的那样
Sorry.
对不起
IV penicillin and anti-TNF antibodies,
给他用青霉素和抗肿瘤坏死抗体
he'll be fine.
他会好起来的
Apart from the whole daddy-rape thing.
除了自己的爸爸强奸自己这件事
We're not done.
这不算完
No, we are not. Notify the dad's sexual partners.
不 当然不算 还要通知他爸爸的性伴侣
Notify his employer, his landlord.
通知他雇主 他的房东
Notify the police. I meant the kid.
- 通知警察 - 我说的是孩子
We're not gonna tell him he was molested?
我们不会告诉他他被强奸过吧?
To make him miserable or to forfeit your license? To tell him the truth.
- 是让他痛苦还是吊销你的执照? - 是告诉他真相
He's a virgin. How do we explain the STD?
他还是个小处男 我们怎么跟他解释性病?
It's a medical diagnosis. Screw the parents. The kid's our patient.
- 这是医学诊断 去他的为人父母的责任吧 - 这孩子是我们的病人
I guess Taub's got a tough choice to make when the kid wakes up.
我想等这孩子醒了 Taub就该有一个艰难的决定要做了
Why is it my choice? 'Cause you're a dad.
- 为什么是我做决定? - 因为你当爹了啊
How could the rest of us possibly understand?
我们这些人怎么能理解为人父母的心情呢
What was... What was wrong with me?
我得了什么病?
It's called syphilis.
它叫做梅毒
Uh, you... you can get that without having sex?
不发生性行为 也能感染上吗?
I didn't tell him.
我没告诉他
Your heart said he needed to know.
你的内心说他应该知道
Your brain knew he's better off without it.
你的大脑知道他不知道的话 会好过一些
Following your heart is easy. Following your brain is tough.
随心而动是简单的 但随脑而动是困难的
Especially after years of following that much smaller third organ.
尤其是在追随着那个小小的第三器官 生活了这么多年后
That's why all parents screw up all children.
这就是所有的父母都会毁掉他们孩子的原因
Evening.
晚上好啊
Clever tactic, pretending you're not interested anymore.
你手段太高招了 假装你不感兴趣了
How could that possibly work as a tactic?
那怎么能说是耍手段呢?
The fact is, once I saw those incompletes, I knew your parents screwed you up.
事实是 我看到你身上的那些缺憾 我就知道你父母毁了你
The details are just gravy.
细节就唾手可得了
You're wrong.
你错了
The only evidence you have is proof of something else.
你手上的唯一证据只能证明别的事情
I ran away from home.
我离家出走过
Because you had lousy parents.
因为你有一对糟糕的父母
Because I didn't.
因为我没有
All my friends' parents were divorced
我所有朋友的父母都离婚啊
or having affairs
或者搞婚外情啊
or barely knew their kids' birthdays.
或者根本不知道他们孩子的生日
You envied their dysfunction?
你嫉妒他们的残缺不全?
I- I thought it made them deeper somehow.
我觉得这让他们更有深度
It was stupid.
这种想法很蠢
I hitchhiked to Manhattan, moved in with an older guy.
我搭车旅行到曼哈顿 和一个比我大的男人住在一起
In two months, I came running home.
两个月里 我不停地离家出走
It took my parents years to get over it.
这让我父母花了很多年 才摆脱我给他们造成的阴影
That's when you started to excel.
从那时起你开始努力
You were making it up to them.
你要补偿他们
Your parents screwed you up by not screwing you up.
你的父母以一种善待你的方式毁了你
How does briefly wishing I was screwed up make me screwed up?
我希望被毁怎么就造成我真的被毁了呢?
It's normal to be screwed up.
被毁了是很正常的
It's really screwed up to romanticize it.
把这个过程浪漫化了就真的毁了这个过程了
I guess that's why you wanted to work with prisoners.
我猜这就是你想和犯人们一起工作的原因
It's why I wanted to work with you.
这是我想和你一起工作的原因
It was a tactic.
我是耍了手段
Chris.
Chris
Yeah. I need to talk to you and Phil.
嗯 我要和你还有Phil谈谈
Is everything okay?
事情都还好吗?
Yeah.
还好
I can't let you move.
我不能让你搬走
You drove all the way out here just to tell us what you already told us.
你大老远地跑来就是为了告诉我们 你已经跟我们说过的话
I'm sorry.
对不起
House, open up. I don't want to miss the opening bell.
House 开门呀 我不想错过开场
House?
House?
Telecast, we expect an electric atmosphere
我们期待竞技场里人们情绪高涨
in the arena and a sellout crowd of about 10,000
我们卖出了一万张门票
for Rubio versus Santos, two great fighters
Rubio与Santos的终极之战 两位伟大的斗士
with illustrious careers who might have been expected to meet a long time ago.
都有着相当出彩的成绩 大家期待两人一决雌雄已经很久了
As for Santos, his handlers tell us that he's done more roadwork
Santos那边 他的经纪人告诉我们
than at any time in his career,
他比以往进行了更多的长跑训练
hoping to prove tonight that he can box for 12 full rounds.
希望在今晚证明他可以打满12个回合
Significant because Santos hasn't heard the final bell
显然是因为Santos已经没听到过终场的铃声
in more than six years.
超过六年之久了
He comes in with 11 straight knockout wins and we saw how a power puncher with a left hook
他挟11连胜的骄人成绩而来 我们见识了他的左勾拳是多么地有力
was able to cut Rubio over the right eye in the tenth round of that last fight.
能在第十回合打肿Rubio的右眼...
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入